foreign
regulator has set an ambitious Target of
insurance for all by 2047 but there is
another Target which the stakeholders of
Indian Insurance ecosystem have been
setting for themselves each day and that
is awareness for all on this insurance
awareness day we are joined by an
eminent panel to speak about the role of
insurance in our lives and more
importantly the role of awareness in
Insurance joining me today is ritesh
Kumar co-chair freaky National Committee
on insurance bhargav Das Gupta chairman
Vicky National Committee on insurance
prashantra party again co-chair Vicky
National Committee on insurance and
finally
presume task force on health insurance
thank you gentlemen for joining us on
CNBC TV 18 today to start with you
bhargav what I want to understand from
you is about this target itself
insurance for all by 2047. in your
understanding is this aim for the moon
and you'll reach the Stars kind of
situation or do you think the industry
if it comes together this target can
actually be achieved
uh thanks Yash thanks for having us
so you know whenever you want to achieve
a transformational change you have to
set uh you know what we call big hairy
auditious goals right and I would
classify this as one of those what we
are seeing the ready to do after talking
about this vicious goal is to look at
the build you know kind of look at the
building blocks to ensure that this
happens and we've seen a lot of Reform a
beat in terms of product uh in terms of
distribution in terms of ease of doing
Insurance business in terms of
attracting Capital that we believe will
uh you know kind of push us in the
direction of achieving this uh you know
objective of insurance for all so no I
don't see this as uh aim for the moon
and reach the Stars we are hoping that
we will aim and Achieve whatever it is
that we are achieving as an industry
Prashant same question to you if this
has to happen of course life insurance
industry also has to play a very
important role ambitious goal but
according to you uh achievable if the
industry puts Collective efforts
absolutely I completely agree with what
bhagava said unless we have vicious
goals how will we achieve uh the good
part is for the first time we have a
goal that we all want to collectively
achieve before this there was no common
question there was no common purpose I
think with the common Vision being there
I think uh the industry along with the
regulator will channelize all the
efforts to ensure that we are
collectively moving in that direction
and under the leadership of our chairman
iidai this vision is acceptable it's a
challenging one I must say at the same
time I don't think it's beyond the realm
of achievement
person coming to you on the same
question in your understanding for the
right assessment of the industry what
should be the order out of penetration
coverage and density
thanks Yash for for inviting me I think
India as a country as you know is both
uninsured as well as underinsured so uh
if you look at health insurance grow to
close to 400 million people do not have
any health insurance coverage or any
retail health insurance you know 300
million people are basically those who
are not a part of any government funded
schemes uh and 10 million are those
people who are you know opting for more
health insurance coverage so around 400
million people is really the target
health insurance segment add up to that
the entire Healthcare inflation which
has been higher than CPI over the last
five years add to that the issue of
India being the diabetic capital of the
world uh add to that that you know and
the recent study has shown uh that uh
average you know middle class family has
to spend one to four times of their
annual income on cardo cardiovascular
diseases and two to seven times of the
annual income uh on any kind of cancer
related diseases and both these two
examples are good enough to show that
you know uh this this can lead to a lot
of distress and can push some people
below the poverty line as well
so I think uh from from all these points
that I said I think all these three are
important but obviously penetration uh
is is extremely important because
because uh India has only around 13 or
14 percent uh of the total population
has got some form of health insurance
either government funded or retail and
output together so a large part of uh
India is uninsured so penetration uh is
really number one and obviously coverage
and density uh are true uh very uh close
number two and number three uh I would
say to ensure uh that we actually get
the overalls uh the aim of you know
insurance for all by 2047. uh prashan
since you're the only one from the life
insurance industry here on the panel
what I want to understand from you is
that as we move towards this target of
insurance for all by 2047 for the life
insurance sector what according to you
quickly would be those three to four
low-hanging fruits that need to be
addressed immediately for you guys to
move ahead smoothly
I think there there are a few and uh um
if you really look at the overall
opportunity I think I will focus firstly
on product and product Innovation I
think that's that's quite required uh
historically life insurance industry has
been quite biased towards selling very
large ticket size I think it has to be
customized to the needs of people and
number two as much as possible digitize
I think
um you know we have not been able to
reach broader masses actually the
penetration is much lower uh if you go
down in the hierarchy of number of
cities and as you go lower and lower uh
that's quite low and you know doing that
completely on the basis of physical
infrastructure physical distribution is
going to be extremely difficult uh
leveraging the overall ecosystem and
leveraging distribution Partners you
could come in the fold and help expand
as soon as possible is the second one or
maybe third one that we could leverage
uh next one to you uh bhargav and ritesh
both you have a lot of portfolios to
look at be it health motor accident so
on and so forth ah starting with you
bhargav in your understanding what are
those three four portfolios where there
are very evident low-hanging fruits
which need to be addressed just look at
certain of the segments that you talked
about in motor for example uh roughly
about 58 of the vehicles on the road
drive without insurance
now there are two issues one is the
compliance and that collectively this is
something that only insurance companies
cannot do but compliance and
distribution both are important
compliance from The Authority side to
ensure that compliance happens and from
the insurance side ensure that that the
product is available and accessible on
health KSI prashun talked about the
numbers clearly we need to figure out a
way to address the affordability
challenge when it comes to the missing
model and when we talk about the
healthcare inflation a person talked
about that and the cost structure that
is that we are seeing I don't think as
an insurance industry we can build
affordability if the healthcare cost is
at that level that it is so collectively
and this is something that we and the
healthcare ecosystem needs to come
together to figure out a way to create
products where uh you know for the
missing middle and the for for the lower
strata of of income hierarchy we find
Insurance Solutions lastly I think there
is a you know tremendous amount of
Reform that we need on the distribution
side the regulator is done uh taking the
first step on the bankertion side but
let's understand the most competent and
expert advice that you can get get when
it comes to insurance at a retail level
is from Agents and at this point in time
agents are allowed to sell only one one
company's products and you know getting
that channel to sell more could be a
massive Game Changer uh same question to
you uh bhargav spoke about compliance
which is very important of course there
were various reports talking about how
uh let's not give fuel to vehicles which
do not have a valid insurance policy so
on and so forth uh how does uh one
really monitor compliance in that on
major portfolios be it health accident
and motor
the whole issue from a compliance
standpoint is is really something which
wherein we need help from the
administration to to ensure that I don't
know I mean it is a menace of vehicles
sort of fly on the road without
insurance now now this is a concern for
the industry as as well as for the sort
of for the authorities now we need to
basically essentially sort of find go
out and find a way that we are able to
ensure this I mean or not not giving
fuel to vehicles which are not insured
is one amongst as sort of the various
sort of possibilities which can be there
but I think what is important is that um
if we are to sort of really go out and
achieve this in fact one of the things
which has also been done is to offer
long-term products around us so so what
what obviously sort of does become very
very important I mean you know is is
that there have to be a number of
measures that need to be taken I mean
you know which are sort of could be
centered around this entire issue of
spreading awareness as to I don't know
how this is mandated by law and
everybody needs to have an insurance
sort of around compliance ensuring that
we get the whole issue of the
accessibility right and then embargov
and sort of prashanth alluded to some of
those things
and of course I mean eventually sort of
address the entire issue of
affordability where to my mind I mean
apart from the various things that we do
and you know if we are able to sort of
address this entire issue around slot
and abuse that helps in to some extent I
don't know in sort of reducing the
traditional cost on that note let's take
a very short break a lot more discussion
coming up on the other side of this very
very short break
foreign